Guide to the Justin Cook Photographs, 2005-2016 RL.11357
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Made in Durham, 2005-2016
  - A community vigil for Jeremy Turner, who was shot to death on May 17, 2011, when he was 19 years old, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 7, Image 032)
    A community vigil for Jeremy Turner, who was shot to death on May 17, 2011, when he was 19 years old. About 100 friends and family gathered on July 17, 2013, at the family home on Gerard Street to celebrate what would have been Jeremy's 22nd birthday. The Religious Coalition for a Nonviolent Durham holds vigils at the site of homicides in Durham as a call for peace, community unity, and healing.
  - Shae Simms gave birth to a son, Bryson DeMarcus China, named after her murdered father Rayburn Antonio DeMarcus Simms, at Duke Regional Hospital in Durham in July 2014 (Box 1, Folder 7, Image 033)
  - Raven Simms, Ray's daughter, shows off her prom dress to her grandmother, Joslin, and her mother, Sheila, in 2013 (Box 1, Folder 7, Image 034)
    Raven Simms, Ray's daughter, shows off her prom dress to her grandmother, Joslin, and her mother, Sheila, in 2013. Raven and her siblings miss Ray the most on holidays, birthdays, proms, graduations, and other milestones. She says her father came to her in a dream a week before her senior prom. He held her tightly, whispered to her that he loved her and that everything was going to be all right. Then he vanished back to his grave.
  - Joslin Simms poses with politicians and gun-control advocates after speaking at a Mayors Against Illegal Guns rally in Chapel Hill in 2014 (Box 1, Folder 7, Image 035)
    Joslin Simms poses with politicians and gun-control advocates after speaking at a Mayors Against Illegal Guns rally in Chapel Hill in 2014. Increasingly isolated by depression and grief, Joslin found companionship and community in organizations like Moms Demand Action for Gun Sense. She and other mothers who have lost their children to violence don't want them to have died in vain, so they have organized with the hope of influencing national and local gun, education and anti-poverty policies.
  - In 2015, Rashard helps demolish and renovate an old restaurant into a new coffee shop in Durham (Box 1, Folder 8, Image 036)
    In 2015, Rashard helps demolish and renovate an old restaurant into a new coffee shop in Durham. He began to piece his life back together as he worked on a construction crew with New Beginnings, a faith-based nonprofit that helps the recently incarcerated find work and stability. Most people with felony records are limited to construction and manual labor.
  - A summer storm rolls in over Angier Avenue and Driver Street in East Durham at sunset, undated (Box 1, Folder 8, Image 037)
  - Joslin in the sunflowers along the Neuse River Trail in Raleigh, N.C., undated (Box 1, Folder 8, Image 038)
  - Reverend Michael Page baptizes Janayah Wallace, 6 at Antioch Baptist Church in October 2013 (Box 1, Folder 8, Image 039)
  - Rashard Johnson spoke on a panel about incarceration at Howard University in Washington, D.C. in April 2015 (Box 1, Folder 8, Image 040)